welcome to the stola the stoah is a
digital campfire where equal hear and
dialogue about what matters most at the
night's edge what's happening now
[Music]
okay so that's recording guys why do
check-ins yeah sure
Jared should go first because he has the
new look for the first chicken mmm yeah
I just got this weird sense of bird
before we joined here I was watching
some music video I hadn't seen for a
really long time so I was like weirdest
al Jaques State as I came in here and
then and then yeah kind of seen being
excited by all this the energy in this
generative space over the past few weeks
that's I'm like very very expansive and
excited for whatever reason at the
moment hmm relishing this moment we're
looking at quite a bit hmm well for me
there are some ominous storm clouds
coming we are hoping for rain and a
little dry there are some ominous
sensations in my body
fear fear sensations the types of
sensations that would warn you of death
or something like that so I'm just
observing those and yeah just kind of
here our house is really kind of crazy
and a good way there's like just kids
running around and everything is a mess
and yeah it's it's been it's been a very
limit all few weeks hmm so when I was
listening to Jarrod there was like a
bubbliness that was just coming arising
and then when I heard Jason it's almost
like like I sunk into the ground and
been a part of like see why these do
work well together so as I was talking
to you guys before I pressed record I
was talking a calling yesterday and you
know it was a great conversation and
then a topic arose in it and it got me
thinking about you guys
and I don't know if the topic was
directly addressed in that conversation
but you know upon reflecting on some
aspects of it the desire to talk to you
guys arose and specifically about this
liminal space that we're in and I I died
out the luminol war I don't know if
that's going to be a good coinage or
descriptive coinage but I think we all
kind of recognize at least in our meta
space that were in this kind of liminal
realm and then just sort of the sort of
the the importance of memetic mediation
in this space right now so yeah I have a
desire just to have an open-ended
inquiry with with you two about that and
yeah I guess I'll just leave it there to
see if anything comes up it's been I
mean I think it's been for me
alternatively surreal and you have very
ordinary at the same time I can like a
surreal ordinariness ordinary because
I'm just at my house you know for day
after day after day you know I think
this is a lot of kills experience kind
of losing track of time
plotting away in the garden taking care
of kids and it's surreal I think the
surreal part is getting online that's
that's what's you know if it was if it
was not that it would seem very just
kind of like it could almost be like a
little vacation right I'm you're still
doing some work but you know workload
we've had to shed a lot of workload so
you know but getting online and you know
witnessing the collective you know
signals that I get you know from videos
and podcasts and feeds it's it's a very
interesting contrast I guess is the word
you know and I you know I don't know if
I've made rational sense of it yet I've
gotten used to it I don't know if I've
conceptualized it in like a meta
framework yet
well I guess to kind of come from the
other opposite direction I suppose yeah
I guess I'm starting to I guess I'm
realizing it's a strange thing in the
sense that so much of what has changed
is actually going more in line mit with
my previous lifestyle so I work remotely
so I'm used to kind of spending time by
myself and you know enjoy my retreat
time too so it's like and it can be
indoors so like that all is very natural
to me and then also to kind of mirror
this kind of like the embodied sense of
being jared is like very you know to use
a Tantra term like very air like it's
kind of blowing around everywhere and
never really calming or grounding and
you know a lot of confusion and
excitement and and yeah I have had to
work with a lot of try to figure out how
to work with that for quite a while
because it's very disorienting and kind
of awkward and I feel like just before
this happened my kind of contemplative
path was starting to get really comfy in
that situation of constant ungrounded
miss ish but it's kind of unground it's
grounded in the underground in this win
the comforts there and so yeah it's the
strangest thing where it actually feels
you know a death is another thing I'm
constantly thinking about and and and
and you go micro you go deaths or quite
common so there's always this impending
doom and my my cycle all my comments I
ecology and stuff like that so yeah I'm
in a weird place where it seems like the
world is now mirroring my my normal some
strange way it's weird I I haven't
really thought about death at all until
today which is strange I it's it's been
kind of like this eternal
where I feel like it's just you know
like it feels like oh my gosh this life
is so long and like it doesn't feel like
you know even just being my age it's
like it's it's like an eternity you know
with an eternity with an eternity and I
started thinking about death just kind
of abstractly like huh you know I did a
couple tweets about it and it wasn't
until like an hour ago where all of a
sudden you know like that it's it's very
familiar feeling I think like it's not
helplessness it's more of like you know
like like my body's starting to process
that death is real again like for a walk
like but so it's not it's not really
intellectual thing it's more of like you
know it's it's kind of the you know I
guess how you put a Jared of like micro
ego deaths you know it's it's kind of I
don't know it is it's kind of a this
process of acceptance embodied process
of acceptance yeah I don't really know
where it came from and maybe it's the
ominous drone clouds coming in yeah it's
weird that there's um the theme that
happened that the stole last week where
death just kept popping up Jared you did
a session on memento mori'
Steven Jenkinson came in to have a
podcast and then Adam ravish did a
philosophy on death and dying so it's
that theme is his present and it's like
it wants to be present in the way mm-hmm
and something that came up when you were
talking Jason a couple of things came up
but I'll mention this one is someone on
Facebook messaged me about like
procrastination and how like retweeted
it as well and some basically
procrastination has this assumption that
you can put things off for tomorrow
right and then the the assumption there
though is that there is tomorrow no and
so he coined the term Antichrist nation
and I thought I'm like wow that really
nails kind of how I feel right now
because it's like the concept of
tomorrow has died for me mmm
and that's why I feel kind of like you
know like we mentioned like you're not
sleeping like I'm what about like a 2:00
a.m. but I feel fine right only babe I
don't feel completely fine but I feel
fine enough to do like you know feel
deployed and do things but yeah it's
like that that idea of tomorrow dying it
feels like the right thing in this
moment yeah I I think um you know the
first thing that kind of comes to mind
as we're talking about death people can
just kind of seem very abstract in the
sense of like does that mean what it
means to for Verve the lights go out but
I think I mean it in a bit of a
different way in the sense that when
there's so much movement and change in
your experience that isn't kind of
grounded in any kind of preconception
over the future or the past or whatever
it is it actually deaf film feels more
like a visceral process to me and and
it's like a process right now to your
point like we can't we can't orient
ourselves in the past because we kind of
see or seeing that like our
infrastructure is not set up to be able
to deal with this type of thing and we
can't ground yourself in the future
because it's so much uncertainty and
there's no idea what next week is going
or tomorrow's gonna look like - you're
mowing and so yeah if you feel like that
you know there is a is a collective
process of death of kind of structures
leaves ideas stories and ideas about
what this was all kind of built on this
fact that you know life was built with
that what the foundations was built on
there's this sense like when I said Oh
death is asking itself to be present or
like is asking us to you know recognize
it right now and
I wonder if that's needed if we're
increasingly becoming or recently
entering this liminal space you know and
if you don't have a good relationship
with death and all the the fears and
emotions that surround it then you know
what's gonna happen when you're like
kike liminal when the liminal war just
is like you know is this chaotic and
like the to kind of go back to the
reason why I wanted to talk to you guys
just to get kind of your sense about
what's happening like maybe we could
like you know like hey what are you
seeing in the in the noosphere right now
in the Internet and then something that
was salient what you said earlier Jason
was like just feels like regular life
right now just hanging out you know like
it feels like a vacation and then when I
plug in online it's like this is just
like a totally difficult you said and
that that online that plugging in online
yeah so I want ask a question I'll just
see how that that landed hmm and my mind
is totally blank blank right now I'm
just I'm feeling I mean I'm definitely
you know we've talked about this before
on our podcast but for me like what I'm
having some kind of insight when I'm
when I'm you know if one heuristic that
I have to know that it's like a real
insight is that there's this kind of
energetic shift in the body you know
oftentimes it's like energy rising up
through my body right now it's kind of
like rising up here and rising up into
my shoulders and my shoulders are like
pretty tense right now but there seems
like there's like energy rising up into
my shoulders and the thing I've learned
is that and this especially happens when
I use cannabis is that it provokes all
kinds of insights and I think in the
past I used to chase those around and
lose my train of thought and get
paranoid and when I learned how to just
kind of like when I'm having these kind
of
strong feelings or emotions that the
worst thing you could do is to block
them off or to try and like like to
tense up because because there's fear
out of fear it's in my experience it
traps that energy in a slightly
different because it got released and it
traps it in a slightly different part of
the body right and that's bad news you
don't you don't want that to happen
because it's gonna it's gonna cause you
it's gonna cause you difficulties down
the road it's gonna affect your
psychology and so it's really just about
like letting it it's like you know just
just it's almost like you're you almost
you know you see people you know like in
certain evangelical churches whether
they're having these kind of like
Kundalini awakening you know in the
Vedic tradition you kind of just have to
let it go and you know sometimes just
like blue and then it's just and it's
just like and then something has changed
you know but you don't really you know
you might not notice it you know for a
long time or ever but something has
changed there's been a slight shift
shift in perception and you're gonna
affect how you structure your how you
create concepts how you you know is it's
it's like a slight and it's sometimes
it's scary like sometimes I have really
disturbing insights like you know like
things of like oh my god really bad
things are coming and I just accept it
or maybe like you know I'm you know
maybe I'm gonna be a part in a really
bad thing that's coming you know Burton
Leah it's like okay accept it and
sometimes I scared you do that because I
don't want to be a bad person right
anyway i I don't know where I'm going
with that correspond with your thoughts
so are you saying that that you this
release was a that bringing this kind of
empty space is that that's where you're
residing right now where you're kind of
things are rico earring and and and are
quite open yeah yeah I mean I mean I'm
in a very open space right now
it's hard for it's hard for me too
it's hard for me to conceptualize things
right now and it's and also my interest
is not really there although I did just
say everything I did required
conceptualization so I want to like
respond to that and also sort of send
the invitation out to three of us right
now that after we press record we can
just delete this thing if any one of us
wants to delete it and that might kind
of free up some some energy so this is
we don't go into like this awesome
perfect plot cast mode you know I I feel
like I'm fluttering in and out of that
and I'm looking what came up there Jason
is something just happened an hour or so
ago like so I just have like this
fuck-you energy coming up on and off
right just like a new most energy and I
always have sort of that energetic kind
of through most quality bubble up but
I've never really like couldn't can
sustain it in a way and never really
kind of like I view like I don't have a
healthy relationship with that state I
guess but it's coming up and I'm
allowing myself to express it and
experience and feel it and then just
it's just a wave just kind of like like
the most asked me to let it in and then
I just like me and Collin we're thinking
about having themes for like danced
existential dance parties and one of
them was Nemo's so I just text color by
the way like I need that do most dance
party and the right away says dude I was
thinking the same thing just you just
launched it and I'm so excited for that
right yeah and it's like it's sort of
like what I got when you were saying
Jason it's like a kind of like a state
emotional emotion comes to you when you
kind of need it in a way and you need to
have a healthy relationship with it yeah
it just occurred to me that that what
you described is is kind of your Damon
you know and whether it's you know
through most or you know one of these
other I guess you would say arc types
that's that's kind of a different way of
translating what I was describing with
like this like kind of on rush of a
certain kind of energy a certain
energetic texture arises and you there's
different ways to handle it you can
handle it internally internally
processing it and that's usually what I
do but you can also externally process
it and of course and I think you've
written about this and some of your
letters Peter of like you know you have
to be a little careful when you when you
do that because it can you know like it
can get out of control right or it can
cause you to do things that maybe you
might later regret but if you've gotten
good if you develop the practice of
harnessing it you know like it seems
like that's what you're doing of like
you know there's overwhelming energy you
call callin and something something
comes out you know comes comes out of it
that I think you know I think that's
really best name I think it's it's it's
an externalization externalizing
processing of what I was talking about
and it's very interesting because I'm
thinking about that in terms of like how
do these we're having these insights
these energies and how do they manifest
in the world you know it seems like
there's like a very quick and fiery
process of like manifesting and
immediately and I think that's that's
what you're doing and then there's like
a much kind of slower process where you
you process it kind of internally but
then you don't really you know maybe a
few weeks later you notice that
something slightly different and your
behavior has been slightly different hmm
so it's like a slower burn and I think
both of them you know both of them have
had their place with among individuals
and within the same individual as well
well I would from a tantra perspective
they like to use the elements just
because these are kind of some of the
fundamental you know they all very are
very distinct in their qualities like
you know flame is very loud and bright
and quick and and can be consumed very
quickly and and then the earth is more
grounded it sounds like Jason's got a
lot of earth and his
his life right now feeling completely
you know in his ordinary situation I'm
also getting on flamewars on the
internet so yeah so there's some fire
blowing in the internet winds of Jason's
experience yeah yeah no but well and I
like the you know using more of Peter
lens to coin a phrase so the diamond or
the the demon I I like to think of it as
kind of like wearing it might be the
same same thing it's located in the same
space
but it comes up wearing different masks
and different types of energies in the
sense that you Moses like you know he's
got a fierce mask on and and has a very
aggressive and quick you know kind of
combat oriented space expression and and
then to kind of take this even more to
get a little bit more tactical of like
what the difference is between kind of
groping with how to embody that Matic
sensations the sensations versus like
really embodying them fully and
skillfully I think you know this is this
is a plug for it for for Colin's dance
party yeah there's this is something we
all know what it's like to like the two
in your head or judging your body as
it's like you just got to get out of the
fuckin way
right what it let the dance dance and
this seemed now that that is the texture
of it and and the more kind of mrs. Webb
embodiment practices are important the
more you awareness you have of the body
in detail the easier it is to feel win
that I mean that that flow is happening
and you're not fighting it mm-hmm so so
like one thing I wanted to flag there is
that you said Damon then you said demon
right away so you had that kind of like
um you you said and then when you said
that I was like huh
so whatever that energy is that we're
sort of talking about if you have a
healthy relationship with it maybe it's
the day one if you have an unhealthy
relationship but maybe it becomes a
demon you know if you're not processing
the anger but you're still following it
or whatever yeah I think it has the same
technology I think it it was it was
co-opted by the Christians maybe earlier
to be this kind of evil thing although
it wasn't always meant
that's at least my very limited
understanding of the etymology of daemon
yeah
what candidate is the good daemon an
angel or is it something else is it like
this kind of trickster who has your best
interest at heart
or maybe not I'm feeling a resistance to
I just simply do the fact like that is a
rich territory that we're getting quite
deep on I wonder if I can kind of pull
this back up a bit into some sense
making and you know maybe throw
something out here it's come up I think
at at least one of the conversations
that Jason I've had while recording for
the podcast
and I think I tweeted about it vaguely
too but I'm seeing I'm feeling a lot of
hopefulness lately in the sense that we
have this very strange situation where
there's two kind of very distinct and
different pressures being that we that
we've been put under and they both are
pointing to more kind of like connection
and conviviality but in very different
ways so one of them is this kind of more
macro kind of meta space of our culture
or broader culture our communities and
everything like that and there's a
strange paradox of I think everybody
feels like more connected in our
isolation you know like it's it's still
but it's it's complicated because we're
in our isolation and and then at the
same time we're also being required to
at least a lot of us are I'm sure look
at what's happening on the ground right
next to us and like you know check in
our neighbors that we never have met and
start to get a local awareness
which is a different type of
conviviality and that one is important
because you know your neighbor doesn't
matter if they're you know Republican or
Democrat like they're your neighbor like
you can't really help who's who you're
gonna be collaborating with and so yeah
it's there's a strange connectedness
that I'm feeling both from a ground-up
perspective and from a kind of you know
isolated together space as well I'm like
really kind of feeling a lot of
hopefulness in the sense that what could
we could we really start moving things
in a little bit more of a collaborative
cohesive way where we respect our
differences
and you know this is this is largely
what Jason and I are trying to do and
the mimetic mediation effort as well so
it seems so of mine with our are kind of
so much of what we're doing and how
we're oriented so I have a desire to
bring heaven and hell back into this
just rush back in the third perfect
I'm feeling that to both things that you
said but then I thought arose like was
just the calm before the storm you know
and it I don't know if I'm being too
dramatic here but maybe there's a fork
in the road that we're faced that you
know the Heaven and Hell fork and and I
wonder just to just throw all the
different topics and the same like agree
the Bulova right now I wonder if the
mediation or some kind of mediation
process to help people navigate the
upcoming liminal space would direct us
in the right direction or the most
heavenly direction I have a few thoughts
some of them are kind of disconnected
let's see if I can connect them so one
going back to what you said Jared is
like I think a week ago I felt hopeful
and now I feel Metta hopeful but I don't
feel hopeful that makes any sense
mmm what I mean is that a week ago I was
thinking along the lines of hey this is
a training ground we're gonna become
more resilient to be able to address our
future challenges you know but going
back to just like my day to day so you
talked about our immediate neighbors
like it's interesting I've been reading
up on the history of this area and it's
a it has
strong you know there's like a strong
kind of mutual aid kind of farming
communities but they've mostly been
decimated in the last unit a few decades
and actually in our little area and
leave in quarantine even because my wife
sister came from Chile and so we've been
basically quarantine a couple trips to
nearby store but like there's really
nobody that lives around here anymore
it's like we're we're in this like
beautiful setting but like we're
completely in a way we're completely
isolated and I we just moved here so we
don't know our neighbors you know we
moved here right when the virus was
starting and so that's strange and then
simultaneously I've been feeling kind of
a sense of exhaustion of you know so
like almost like too much social
socialising online where because it's a
little bit more disembodied than usual
it's actually more exhausting and I've
been feeling a need to like pull away
and just kind of like go down into my
deep dark tunnel and see what arises
from that and so it's kind of the
opposite of what jerez talking about but
what I'm also noticing in terms of
memetic mediation is that it feels like
some seeds that have been planted before
like I was just speaking in my own
experience are starting to germinate in
terms of like noticing alliances
shifting and very interesting
developments in terms of like you know I
don't want to get too much into detail
not just on all mysterious but like some
you know just recently you know
community that I've been interacting
with online you know like some very
interesting developments have happened
there in terms of how they're being in
the world that I find very positive but
also very I'm almost hyperventilating is
it's positive in a sense but also like
like they're also recognizing the
like they're recognizing things that I
want them to recognize but the things
that are recognizing that they're
recognizing are very ominous do you I
know I know this is sounding really
abstract but I don't want to go into
details with names and stuff because you
know it's just it doesn't feel like the
appropriate time yeah I think I know you
talk about you want to press record stop
pressing record and chat about it
even then I feel like I'd be betraying
some trust it's just not the right time
okay maybe I don't know who you're
talking about
yeah we have the bromance and I have no
idea I mean I'm making it maybe I'm
making it sound more dramatic like I was
it was feeling dramatic for me but I
think in the in the larger scheme of
things I'm sure if I mentioned it it
maybe wouldn't seem so dramatic but it's
it's like just like there's certain
shifts in kind of the the mimetic tribal
landscape that I find incredibly
intriguing and fascinating one in
particular that this is just just kind
of you know came to my doorstep like
yesterday and today yeah I definitely
want to talk about it while recording
again I'm not trying to get all style
mysterious and like oh this is likes to
see too late that was one of the one of
the can from an external perspective I
guess gotcha
and that was one of the like maybe the
things I wanted to chat about just like
to what's happening because I've been so
like absorbed with the stoah I haven't
been really like track in a culture war
as good as I could so part of the reason
why but at parents of mystery we we
cannot know yeah I mean it's tough
because you know I've been kind of
overwhelmed with some of the social
media front for the past few months I'm
not as as dialed in that being said
there's been you know some of the the
distinct tribes that I follow you know
in the contemplative space and the
podcast
kind of betterment and development space
I've started to interact and I've seen
people talking to each other that I
didn't expect to tweets liked to reply
its to folks by you know it it does seem
like there is a blurring of lines
happening right now and I think largely
you know that's that's what happens when
all of these kind of memetic tribes move
into a place of liminal space like this
they have just kind of start opening
their ears and eyes and seeing like
what's on round as opposed to being so
interiorly focused and so yeah I would
expect a lot of a lot of interaction and
so far I haven't seen a huge amount of
drama but I'm sure there will be
definitely some collisions and maybe
we'll have some of those Wars lesson
battles coming up in the coming weeks
and months so so what's coming up there
is that like going back to calm before
the storm and there's just the imagery
that came to mind I don't know where
it's coming from but like maybe we're at
this space right now where you know
everyone's kind of looking around they
feel something ominous is coming and so
they want to be friend you know former
enemies and so this is like a nice space
to be in right now collectively but then
if things start like deteriorating
society like society like you know some
collapsing era starts happening maybe
some civil war or whatever occurs in the
next couple of months then all that
goodwill that got built up home you know
evaporates yeah I mean so we're in this
interesting liminal space but you know
most of us of course some people are you
know fighting in the pit of hell right
now if you're you know a medical worker
in New York City right now I can't even
imagine but you know for most of us it's
like this liminal space but but most of
us are doing okay right and right and so
the liminal space part is as you guys
both said it's kind of reorganize like
like one people have talked a lot about
this where you know what's essential you
know people to people are having
conversation about our central workers
you know what are essential aspects with
the economy and there's a lot of you
know this reorganization is you know
it's
is partially due to like oh well you
know what we're more open to seeing to
seeing you know alliances where maybe
they didn't you know occur before why as
you're saying but and but if if things
really really starts hitting the fan and
I could especially if supply chains
start breaking down and things like that
I'm not sure like I definitely think it
would it would move into like it's right
right now it's very internal like
there's there's new alliances but
they're also there's also new enemies
right and and there's there's further
there's more distinctions as well so as
we go back to my saying before the thing
that's happening is that kind of a
broader group that I thought was kind of
like part of the same group is now you
know like there's you know there's
there's awareness forming that like
within that group certain certain
certain people are seeing other parts of
that group is an enemy or is a bit a
huge danger right so there's also
greater distinctions I think that are
going on and so this kind of liminal war
so to speak like there's a lot of you
know there's a lot of private
conversations going on I guess say not
to get na starts downing Elkins because
yeah yeah well and to kind of continue
Peters battle metaphor and they like the
image of you know kind of all of these
armies you know walking out to this big
battlefield that like we're all realized
that it could potentially be wartime in
existential sense and you know
everybody's kind of like waiting for you
know waiting for the virus to roll in
and we're kind of talking to each other
about how we want to take things on and
and you know everybody at least feels
like there's some good faith in the
sense that we're all kind of united in
our in our direction and what we want to
solve but yeah there's a bunch of sizing
up and and I think that the the
definitive thing here is is to Jason's
what it's like how bad things get
because soon as scarcity gets ratcheted
up to a certain atom of intensity and
many survival mechanisms kick in and we
start
you know real tribal you know ancient
tribal shit and so yeah it's I think
that the scarcity dimension is the one
that we should want to keep the closest
dial on to see how severe the kind of
backlash and war will actually be but
you know if we're lucky it's stays
manageable and we come out the other end
making some you know broadening some
perspectives and making some peace and
some treaties or something I don't know
I'm liking this metaphor but I might be
torturing it yeah I yeah just to
reiterate what you're saying Jared I I
do I do think that you know as you and
as you mentioned earlier Peter like we
can kind of go and there's many
directions that society can go on right
now and I think it is you know there's a
part of me that's hopeful that you know
the the kind of the networked
alternative to the establishment which
you know exists both on the left on the
right you know and people you know and I
know like Jack Murphy is really talking
a lot about this and you're having him
on the stoah he's definitely more on the
right right like he's a trump supporter
but he's he's you know he has people
like Jordan Hall and John rabe and and
these guys and and you know this this
idea this kind of network alternative
that's collectively intelligent this
collective intelligence if it pulls
together and this is where you know some
of the informal minimag mediation work
that many of us have been doing like
reaching out different people you know
if if those start to bear fruit and this
kind of networked alternative can can
you know get together and you know align
incentives in order to produce you know
very intelligent you know alternative to
to the you know collapsing I don't know
collapsing institutions then things can
turn out really well and we would come
out of this much better prepared for
what I see is much bigger future
challenges having to do with you know
our ecological realities so that's
that's the hopeful part of me but I'm
also aware that
there's a lot of groups that see this as
a moment you know don't waste a don't
waste a crisis right and there's a lot
of very ideological groups that have a
lot of you know designs for you know
what kind of society they want to see
you know utopian designs that frankly
some of them are pretty scary so there's
that as well yeah I know you talked
about noise yeah yeah and then the the
whole thing about death you know it's
like in order to run with that
hopefulness or transmit that hopefulness
to deployment it's like almost you have
to have a right relationship with the
opposite happening or thinking of the
worst-case scenario happening and like I
was telling Jared I think when I was
talking to him earlier today I was we're
talking with the stoah and and I feel
like it's like I'm the right person to
be a steward for a space like this and I
was saying like the three kind of
characteristics is that I have the you
know the deal I was a Dale Carnegie
trainer so I'm like even though no one's
training a person anymore you know so I
have that interpersonal skills like a
network I've been charming whatever I
have that that culture war ability to
take multiple perspectives and and I
have an ego but my ego at least I don't
think it is attached to my ideas like
it's like I could make criticized on the
white paper I don't care whatever right
and so I think that affords me to just
invite all sorts of different people
into the space and maybe that could and
when not now I'm kind of like bringing
up the magnetic mediation again maybe
there's an opportunity here for a
magnetic mediation with that and and I
guess this is like this conversation
maybe finding itself right now and I
know both of you along with myself and a
few other people in our slack group are
interested in mimetic mediation so I
wonder how we could be deployed so we've
we've uh so we've talked about this in
the past and you Peter
I put it out there that you know so we
were writing an article together and I
think we just we were kind of coming at
it from different places and we decided
that it would be best to write separate
articles the way that I approach it and
that's why it's kind of hard for me to
write about is that for me it's very
informal it's it's a way of being it's
it's like for me it's like my informal
interactions you know first of all and
I'm doing this online of course you know
in in in body space it's a little bit
different but I'm doing it online you
know it's very small things you know
it's it's you know it's it's banter with
you know with people that you know even
though we might have very different
ideas it's you know a certain you know
it's it's joking it's ribbing each other
it's no jumping in it you know
connecting in DMS over you know some
musical artists or like it's it's just
it's like the accumulation of a million
small things that I that I'm you know
kind of a you know there's kind of an
awareness like it's a lot of it's just
kind of instinct roll an intuitive but
there's also kind of awareness that like
okay I don't like I like starting to
build some connections here and in my in
my paper of my creation I actually
related to the Kagan stages as is
related to different as an analogy for
different lenses of mediation and the
one that I think is the most important
is the stage three lens which is the
relational lens and it's kind of sub
ideological and to me that's actually
the that's like that that's like the
most fun and I think the most it's not
it's it's it's not sufficient but it's
it's one of the most powerful lenses in
terms of just building relationships you
know in in in and whatever kind of way
you connect with somebody aesthetically
you know anything you know we're a a
shared interest in permaculture whatever
whatever whatever right and and later
you know when you talk start talking
about ideology and ideas there's a lot
more good faith that I found is extended
in like trying to understand each other
when you've established a more just
purely relational base
and so you know what I'm you know and so
in terms of like how we can extend this
remediation I think for me it's just
doing the same thing that I've been
doing that I sound really arrogant or
something but I I feel like you know
like that's just what I'm kind of
continuing and I feel like some of the
relationships I've built you know are
starting to you know I hate to they pay
off but like like you know it's you know
like people like you know are taking me
in certain comp you know in kind of
confidence you know occasionally that
you know providing me with really
interesting information and maybe useful
information right that you know wouldn't
have been available otherwise if you
hadn't built that relationship right
yeah well and and so normally I would I
would say the exact opposite but I
actually agree in a lot of ways in the
sense that I very much see the mimetic
mediation I think that there are well I
think it's a byproduct of acting and
embodying a kind of meta tribal
perspective so the simple fact that as
you said Peter you can kind of wear the
different lenses of the different of
different tribes and kind of like chair
to please look at them and don't feel
any kind of like you made you know major
emotional capture by any anyone I think
we all have some residue you know it's
it's not not completely black and white
but but you know if if you were
interacting with that orientation the
medic mediation is happening regardless
and and I think the stoah is actually a
perfect example of that in the sense
that you've got this a collective group
of thinkers and practice and you know
and practitioners and dancers and
everything in between right who are
being introduced to each other and you
know kind of there's a lot of tribal
cross-pollination happening on the stoah
so so yeah but to your point Peter I
mean I do still think there are ways
that norms and and and things that we
could start to
rituals or or best practices or whatever
we want our KPI is I mean you frame this
in a and a business economic spiritual
way lens I think we could look at
figuring out how to create some
structures from this meta tribal lens
that kind of make these systems a little
bit more inherently grass pollinate
cross pollinating and not so isolated
and yeah nothing at the moment is he's
coming super to mine but something's
coming mind for me so related to that
you have a sure thought first and know
kind of like leading to maybe and open
inquiry for like another fifteen ten
minutes for us yeah that was really good
what both of you said and feeling like
you know when ayran issue said oh how
could we like deployment medic mediation
it was like some some of the to Moses
leaking through I don't know if this is
the right moment for it to leak through
but and there's also like I wanted to
please what I just said was like you
know you use it's important to stay in
your lane right you don't want to
overextend yourself and I was thinking
of what Jason you know he's doing what
he's doing right now and I'm like when I
what I'm doing and how that helps
mimetic mediation because the stoah and
I'm viewing the stove as a digital
campfire and Richard Bartlett came in
earlier today he kind of like he's doing
this regular collaboration workshop so
if you have a collaboration issues or
you have a community he just kind of
like stress test you and stuff yeah
though he did his first session with me
and the stoah right so it's kind of like
it really helped me kind of understand
what the space is and everyone was
talking about hierarchies forming this
and that and I'm like I think we want to
think about the word hierarchy right
it's like I don't want to deal with that
stuff and then I'm like yeah the only
thing I want is to make sure this fire
keeps burning hmm this digital can't
fire I just want to make sure this fire
keeps burning and this sort of like the
Damon I just want I just want to keep
lighting myself on fire and I just want
to keep it burning and then people can
come and gather around and they can
leave and they do what they want with it
but when you're talking about how store
could be a place for people to come in
and make
together and mediate and maybe all I
have to do is just have that fire
burning still and I have a practical
thing to kind of want to workshop with
you guys maybe for 10 minutes but
curious anything came alive when I said
that the analogy of keeping the fire
burning was intriguing to me like it
almost like so what do we keep it
burning with well all of our
preconceptions about what it should be
or our agenda for it is like the
kindling or the wood paper fire oh shit
it's like that's good and it's like well
how do we anything anything we can we
can possibly do to keep the fire burning
and so like a you know whatever we need
to burn whether it's you know whether
it's a certain hierarchical structure or
where there is a certain totally
pluralistic microstructure or whether
it's you know this person leading or you
know like whatever you know whatever you
whenever you see the fire losing its you
know losing its warmth you know whatever
these logs are usually throw them in and
keep it burning whatever you have to do
and that that was very intriguing to me
not amazing yeah that really just
enriched its a fire metaphor of course
the other thing that comes to mind is
that if we're doing that how do we
ensure that the fire you know
maintains its its overall morality right
so you know burning the fire at all
costs you know you know if you're if
you're burning if you're starting to
burn some fundamental ethics or some you
know certain things that's some
fundamental values that you hold for it
you know like a fire burning at all cost
you know you know I mean I have a desire
to like save that metaphor by saying
like you know if you try to burn
something Noble then that's like
throwing water on it or something
mmm and like if you extinguish the fire
then you know like you don't have any
heat you might die to the cold so I hope
that safe that delicious metaphor that's
building up
beautiful and take it away right away no
well yeah I love the fire metaphor and
and yeah I mean this is this is the
coolest thing about yeah this is another
example of what it's some sort of
enabling constraint can be can create
enabling constraint here is this this
metaphor of the campfire and it's so
rich because there's so many dimensions
in which you're with this orientation in
mind you can kind of consider different
perspectives otherwise it's just
overwhelming there's too much to see so
that's why you know it's kind of
ridiculously you know intellectually VAS
purgatory it can be to torture metaphors
I actually think that this is these are
you know these are tools that we can use
very wisely so that being said a few
more dynamics of the campfire that I
think might be fun to explore one of
them Jason already mentioned but the
temperature right there's a there's
there's a a a right amount of fire that
is warm and inviting not big enough to
the point where nobody can you know
people can't see on the other side you
know this kind of speaks to the growth
of it I think there's probably it
probably gets too big or it starts to
have to be franchised there could be
multiple fires that would pop up so that
everybody can see each other and and in
this seeing part is so important too
because you know when we're talking
about hierarchical capture and a lot of
the negative dynamics that come from
that so much of that about what that is
about is that certain people are able to
kind of hide from from the others and so
you know making sure that there's their
route right amount of visibility or you
know if we're gonna put in business
terms transparency into what's happening
who's involved and and everything like
that I think is you know one of the the
kind of safeguards that you would want
to employ here and and that meaning you
know certain Kendall would be would burn
brighter than others right and so you
don't want it to run on coals only or
something like that so so keeping a
diverse a diverse selection of wood but
the coals are important too yeah we
could probably you can
just do hold a business design and
you're just like the campfire all the
components of the campfire so the the
thing I wanted to workshop it probably
is too late now and maybe I'll just flag
it we can we can bookmark it for another
time but that campfire thing like oh so
is there a session that we can design at
the campfire that's about mimetic
mediation right like I talked about the
anti debate idea you know I wrote an
article I like could we port some of
this stuff here because if this is
really the calm before the storm now is
the perfect time to get these people to
actually dialogue with each other
especially these important notes and
really kind of put them like to the fire
in a way like you know the the hold them
to it
their their truth so I'm wondering if
anything like that could be designed and
I say the first thing that jumped into
my mind was you know like we mentioned
that the lot of the reason that that our
different warring tribes are talking to
each other and there seems to be a
little bit more goodwill is simply due
to the common intention for what we're
addressing and you know the covet is
rich with a million dimensions that we
can approach this from you know what do
we need to be doing better locally what
we do and doing better virtually and
whatnot it would be really fun to see
some of these intellectuals that you've
invited that normally would never talk
to each other all come and just have a
conversation about that one topic that
obviously we can all agree on right now
right that's really good I think one way
to make that happen is to invite them
individually first by the campfire make
them comfortable with it have a good
time with it and then bring them all
together yeah yeah yeah I mean I want to
see Jordan and and Zach Zach Stein and
Rankin yeah rikiei talks to us too but
yeah I don't know I'm sure there's some
combinations that I haven't thought of
that even of the folks that you've
already had on
super interesting I can think of one
match right now that would be very very
juicy should I say it is it isn't a
mystery Jason well so earlier today
Richard Bartlett he mentioned you know
he was criticizing the meta space for
not really amounting to much and he
mentioned for example you know nobody's
really successfully integrated like
intersectionality and conservatism and
then Jack Murphy came in and said like
are you serious cuz you know you know
when you mentioned intersectionality you
know Jack Murphy's alarm bells go off
right like he's he's very you know in
some ways he's very and I you know anti
any of that and and then Marley
responded saying you know no like I was
flexing like no you it was basically
like you know challenge see their room
together and oh my goodness see this is
like I'm just what I'm missing out on
this stuff and the interesting thing is
that they're both interested in kind of
decentralized organizing like that's
what they're gonna know about yet you
know this this this issue of you know
the word that some people have an
allergy to and means different things
different people my goodness so it has
no would keep apart people who would
actually probably work really well
together in many other dimensions that
this is the first I think that's an
amazing idea and then and it's very
doable because Richard is a regular kind
of fetus he's come on poisonous though I
he's gonna come on next week Jack's
coming on and he's retweeting a lot
about the stories like you retweeted a
call and more dance party I'm like
really you think okay thanks and he I'm
being into that yeah and I never like he
invited me to his podcast like months
ago but we never like just made it
happen and so you know so he's come on
the stone now I never really talked to
him before I don't know much about him
to be honest besides I know his
reputation of the nanosphere or
tremendous for your Trump guy but I
think that could happen because Richard
is really open to talk to different
voices yeah and then if Jack Murphy is
an alpha male I'm sure he's not gonna be
shy either so that's definitely how
Richard you know
that's how Richard related to him is
like yeah man I'm flexing no you know I
like about what we just had right there
is this like this could be a TV show or
like a youtube series his own podcast
like you know like fight cards for the
magnetic mediation like campfire that's
really good yeah well we need Jason and
I need to host a you know an epic brawl
with all of the the meta tribes we'll
get the integral people will get the
Hansie folks will get the you know the
cultural aesthetic folks like I mean
most that campfire and watch it another
thing I can think of right now is being
a and Jim rut being a Gupta Jim rut oh
boy there was a huge explosion game be
around those those folks and that would
be a fiery one another one where they're
both you know incredibly intelligent
people a lot of their ideas align with
each other but a few key kind of
allergies you know caused this explosion
I think like I can tell you a little bit
more about that maybe after sugar core
okay more that allergies going on there
oh yes so the last thing I'll say maybe
just to get you guys advice so there's
just one connection I've made and I feel
quite strong about it is that in order
to maintain this relationship with the
Dame on or to Kindle the fire is that I
just really have to be fucking truthful
mmm very nice really have to be truthful
at all times
and the last two days I just really been
kind of like plugged in and in that way
and I'm talking online right now as I
would like with my most comfortable
friend you know or the friend I'm most
comfortable with and then when I
recorded the Richard Bartlett wanted and
posted yet I just felt really vulnerable
and then just thinking about posting
this one I feel really vulnerable well I
don't actually don't feel that
vulnerable right now because I'm just
having a good time with you guys but
thinking about posting it at bonner
ability might merge again and I don't
know what that is but maybe was fear of
you know broadcasting things up being
misunderstood being weaponized all the
type of things yeah and not really
trying to police an impression yeah yeah
this is a big one for me in the sense
that you know I went through a kind of
radical truth phase where I was like
we'll never say a lie ever again you
know very dogmatic about it and I think
what I discovered is that there's a many
ways to wield the truth untruthfully and
the whether you know it's true or not is
simply what your point - and that's the
sense is their vulnerability here so
yeah I think the vulnerability is is
actually the juice of truthfulness that
you know it's a little as a layer lower
but far more essential I think here and
yeah it's risky because that's right
yeah I I don't really you know whether
you want to you want to post this or not
I really am I'm really it would be very
okay
either way yeah I could go down a whole
whole tangent about about you know
radical truth and I've had I've gone
through a rollercoaster with that kind
of thing to the point where I started
become very neurotic about it and and I
had to from my perspective develop a
much more you know I used to I went
through a period where I would if my if
I had a restful point in my mind I'm I
would automatically start looking for
something to feel guilty about in terms
of like oh when I was talking to that
person three days ago I might have
slightly misrepresented something and
like it would just tear me up inside and
so I and so like for me there's this
kind of like you know anyway that's the
whole tangent and I don't know where
that's leading me but the truth is
complicated the truth is well yeah and
and and you know for me it's about the
next moments you know trying to trying
to do the best I can but also when I
notice that like oh like things weren't
perfect not you know not always feeling
like I need to go confess or that I need
to feel guilty it's like that's learning
and I think I've you know
yes I kind of outgrown the radical truth
kind of fire because I find that at
least two neuroses at least in my case
but I try to be truthful you know in the
moment but I don't retrospectively lash
myself right yeah I have a desire like
yeah it's not that strong of a desire
but I felt both of what you said and I
agree with components of it or I agree
with the perspective let's put it that
way even though I might not I might have
a different perspective right now and
then this perspective I have right now
and an almost experience of it is cyber
radical honest got Brad Blanton when I
was younger and I just went through this
kind of like there's crazy truth phase
and I just like well there was a truth
ray and then like you know sometimes it
was just like oh my god why did I say
that in retrospect but sometimes I was
like wow it was great because it was so
I'm not talking about that type of truth
I get to say everything at all times
it's more like it's like Gregory Kramer
the guy who invented inside dialogue he
called it a truth power it's like the
way I hold that is like the truth that
demands to be spoken you know that that
type of thing and then you be truthful
with that like there's so much things I
can be truthful with like oh there's a
microphone right here there's a table
whatever right but this that's not the
truth that's alive right now and so it's
almost like that truthfulness muscle
like fuse with the damon or whatever
that spirit is um and i feel like i'm
doing that if i'm doing anything in the
last two days yeah there seems like yeah
yeah it seems like expressing letting
the the demons express itself is the
truth is the truthfulness right like
what's real for you at that moment
bringing up unapologetically yourself
and but that doesn't mean that after we
wrap this and we reflect on what we were
saying you can't have a diamond say yeah
that's probably not good for public you
know those yeah it's it's the the
decisions in the moment it can't be
quantified or turn into
an equation now can I read a quote this
is a quote from a lot of thunder the
blind faith I think so it goes even as
it has been said quote not everything
that a man knoweth can be disclosed nor
can everything that he can disclose be
regarded as timely nor can every timely
utterance be considered as suited to the
capacity of those who hear it well I
think that I think that's that's
reinforcing where you're saying Jared
and so yeah I I would agree that I I you
know for me what when you're feeling
kind of this juice that or this fire
that's fueled by a certain vulnerability
you want to express it like that's I
think that's the best definition of
truthfulness
you know expressing what you're really
thinking in the moment but what you do
with that and how you how you wield that
in this case how we wield this kind of
recording you know takes wisdom right
right right
yeah I love it and I'll say this then
I'll stop the report button
so I there was a fear in me about
thinking about releasing that Richard
Bartlett one and there was a fear in me
earlier this conversation but releasing
this one it's not present right now so
we'll see what happens later and what
was the other thought that I had that I
wanted to close with yeah it was this
this whole kind of conversation that we
had it's recorded right we don't know if
we're gonna release it you know we don't
know we're gonna do with it like we were
in the luminal state in a way like going
out of different realities throughout
this whole conversation and I thought
that this was like a nice artistic
experience having this recorded and no
don't knowing with the reality of what's
going to be afterwards right we're
recording in the liminal space of you
know this is the light package this is a
single tank the reality of that you know
in the back of our minds whether we want
to know it's a little bit of a
performance but at the same time the
other reality is that we're just
connecting as bro's
yeah yeah
I don't know let's get Jason secrets out
of them